Jessica Eubanks

1707 Spyglass Drive #60 Austin, TX 78746 Phone: 512-297-3671 E-mail: LSUgirl@gmail.com

Summary

I am a highly motivated, self-starter with reputation of learning new skills quickly. I have over 12 years' experience leading development teams in design of new web applications, system migrations and internal infrastructure changes. I have over 20 years solid programming experience and am innovative in resolving unusual problems. I have a Master's In Business Administration with a focus in Management Information Systems.

Skills

VS .NET C# (18 years), SQL Server DB (11 years), Sitecore CMS (2 years), ASP.NET (15 years), MVC (6 years), nTier/Object Orientated Development (18 years), ADO (15 years), Crystal Reports (15 years), Amazon Web Services (4 months), REST APIs (10 years), Web Services (10 years), ETL (5 years)

Experience

Senior Application Developer/ Contractor (April 2019 – July 2019)

Randstad at Trident Research

Description: Developed prototype web application to attract potential investors.

Technologies and tools used: Visual Studio 2019 .NET Framework 4.5, C#, ASP.NET, ReShaper,

GIT, Amazon Web Services (DynamoDB, ElasticBeanstalk, S3, IoT), Google Maps API

Responsibilities and accomplishments:

- Created new architecture for web application connecting 5 web cameras via cellular connection.
- Implemented solution using Amazon Web Services for scalability.
- Developed 6 page web application including login functionality, real time video, telematics and GPS location.

Lead Developer (July 2017 - April 2019)

University of Texas at Austin, McCombs School of Business (Austin, TX)

Description: Developed and maintained external facing website for the business school.

Technologies and tools used: Visual Studio 2015, .NET Framework 4.5, C#, ASP.NET, MVC, SQL Server DB, ReShaper, GIT, JIRA,, Sitecore CMS

Responsibilities and accomplishments:

- Mentored junior developers and handled code reviews.
- Coordinated developers to allocate resources to ensure efficiency and productivity are maximized.
- Shared extended knowledge regarding software upgrades and migrations.
- Work in Agile work environment with daily SCRUM meetings.

Programmer V (July 2014 – July 2017)

Texas Education Agency (Austin, TX)

Description: Developed and maintained internal web applications for state education agency dealing with state funding.

Technologies and tools used: Visual Studio 2013, .NET Framework 4.0, C#, ASP.NET, MVC Oracle DB, Crystal Reports, NHibernate, ReShaper (code review)

Responsibilities and accomplishments:

- Mentored new developers and QA.
- Coordinated staff and allocate resources to ensure efficiency and productivity are maximized.
- Designed and developed web applications for internal state funding tracking.
- Work with customer on requirements and user acceptance testing.
- Work in Agile work environment with daily SCRUM meetings.

Senior Programmer (October 2013 -April 2014)

Springbox (Austin, TX)

Description: Developed internal and external websites for customers such as Dell, PayPal and Kele.

Technologies and tools used: Visual Studio 2012, .NET Framework 4.0, JavaScript, C#, ASP.NET, Sql Server DB, Kentico CMS, Ektron CMS

Responsibilities and accomplishments:

- Developed web segments for customer websites for marketing purposes.
- Optimized SQL Server queries to speed up dashboard web pages.
- Trained and mentored junior programmers in C# and SQL Server principles.
- Estimated workhours for new projects.

Senior Programmer Analyst (April 2013 -October 2013)

Whole Foods - Global Support (Austin, TX)

Description: Designed and developed web application to be used national by regional offices and stores.

Technologies and tools used: Visual Studio 2012, .NET Framework 4.0, JavaScript, C#, ASP.NET, Sql Server DB, Team Foundation Server, TIDAL (task scheduler)

Responsibilities and accomplishments:

Designed and built new web applications.

- Maintained and monitored scheduled tasks for recipe and ingredient costing.
- Worked in Agile work environment with daily SCRUM meetings.
- Created multiple databases and lengthy stored procedures to utilize third-party database for our needs.

Team Lead/ Senior Developer (February 2006 -April 2013)

US Department of Labor - Job Corps Data Center (Austin, TX)

Description: Designed and developed large scale business web applications for national federal data center serving over 14,000 users daily.

Technologies and tools used: Visual Studio 2005/2008/2010, .NET Framework 3.x and 4.0, JavaScript, ASP.NET, MVC, C#, Sybase DB, NHiberate, ADO, MS SQL Server, StarTeam (source control), nUnit, CruiseControl (build process), AquaData (database query), ReShaper (code review), Crystal Reports

Responsibilities and accomplishments:

- Designed, built and implemented over 12 new web applications.
- Team Leader for 7 years over as many as 7 team members including senior developers, QA and BA members.
- Utilized nUnit to unit test applications and test driven development (TDD)
- Worked in Agile work environment with daily SCRUM meetings.
- Migration from Sybase DB to SQL Server DB rewriting over 400 stored procedures and creating 50 new indexes

Application Developer / Architect (April 2004 - February 2005) Durcon Labs (Taylor, TX)

Description: Designed and developed bid management application that tracked quoted bids from creation to fulfillment.

Technologies and tools used: Visual Studio 2005, .NET Framework 2.x, ASP.NET, C#, ADO, MS SQL Server, SourceSafe (source control), Crystal Reports, CSLA (Component-based Scalable Logical Architecture).

Responsibilities and accomplishments:

- Designed and developed nTier web application for internal use.
- Mentored a junior developer in application development process.

Systems Programmer/ Analyst (January 1998 -March 2003)

Evolutionary Technologies International (Austin, TX)

Description: Developed ETI Solution Version 5 (data migration application). Developed internal CRM and Accounting systems.

Technologies and tools used: Visual Studio, .NET Framework 1.x, ASP.NET, ADO, MS SQL Server, SourceSafe (source control), Crystal Reports, Clarify (CRM), Epicor (Accounting).

Responsibilities and accomplishments:

 Developed ETI Solution Version 5 (data migration application) in Microsoft .NET technology and Visual C#.

- Participated in the Microsoft .NET beta site testing. ETI was one of the first companies to release a .NET application.
- Trained programmers on the basics of Windows-based programming.
- Implemented and maintained several in-house applications such as Epicor (accounting), Clarify (CRM) and Actuate (reporting).
- Trained and mentored new programmers on the MIS team.

Senior Programmer/ Team Lead (October 1994 - January 1998) Kasle Steel (Dearborn, MI)

- Developed and maintain order management system that tracked orders, inventory and process flow of steel through 4 steel processing plants with over 100 users.
- Provided training and resources for the users of the application.
- Team leader for 3 years over as many as 4 programmers.

International Investment Consultant (August 1992 -September 1994) Chen and Associates (Baton Rouge, LA)

- Responsibility for more than \$10 million in foreign investment.
- Wrote international investment newsletter with a circulation of 500.
- Wrote Microsoft Access database application for better management of investment opportunities. Was able to resell this application as an external product.

Education

Master of Business (MBA) (May 1992)

Management Information Systems University of New Orleans New Orleans, LA

Bachelor of Science (May 1990)

Finance Louisiana State University Baton Rouge, LA